Windmuller, John Additional Papers /4146
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
John Windmuller Additional Papers
1951-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Windmuller, John P.
/4146
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
3108484
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 13, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 03, 2016
Biographical / Historical
John P. Windmuller (December 4, 1923 December 2, 2003) was Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of the University of Illinois (BA, 1948) and Cornell University's ILR School (PhD, 1951), Windmuller joined the Cornell University faculty in 1951. He was appointed the Martin P. Catherwood Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations in 1983. He was named professor emeritus in 1987.
An expert in the study of international and comparative labor relations, Windmuller authored many books and reports on the topic, among them Collective Bargaining in Industrial Market Economies: A Reappraisal (ILO, 1987) and Labor Relations in the Netherlands (Ithaca: Cornell, 1969). With Alan Gladstone, he edited Employer Associations and Industrial Relations: A Comparative Study (New York: Oxford, 1984).
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor John Windmuller: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18116
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3028: John P. Windmuller Records /4046: ILR School Historical School Documents /4065: John P. Windmuller Additional Papers /4158: John P. Windmuller Additional Papers
Windmuller, John P.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3108484
- Foreign Students As Hoc Committee, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Graduate Committee 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Investments and Public Policy Committee, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Planning and Personnel Policies Committee Minutes, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Planning and Personnel Policies Committee, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Planning and Personnel Policies Committee 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Planning and Personnel Policies Committee 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Program Planning, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- University Committee IX, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Cipolla, Carlo University, of California, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cook, Alice, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Faupl, Rudolph, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Faculty Planning Committee 1954-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Graduate Committee 1965- Minutes (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Graduate Committee 1965- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 15)
- International and Comparative Labor Relations - 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Undergraduate Program Committee, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- International Activities Committee Material, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- International Activities Com. Minutes 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Division of International Activities, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous 1961 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous 1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous A-E 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous F-J 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous K-O 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous K-O, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous P-T 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous P-T 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous U-Z 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous 1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous 1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous 1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Standard Oil Company, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- ILO Institutes, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Assistant Professor Vacancy -- B. Herrick, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Arbitration: Brodie Industrial Truck, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Arbitration Bell Neckwear Company, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Arbitration Doeskin Products, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Annals, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Brookings Institution, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Burtch. Jeff, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Catherwood M.P., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Council on Foreign Relations, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Dunlop, John, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Education + World Affairs, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- European Trade Union Secretariat, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Foreign Visitors 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Foreign Visitors 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Foreign Visitors 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Fund for International Social + Economic Education, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- German Correspondence 1957-1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- German Correspondence 1955-56, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- German Correspondence 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- German Correspondence 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Guggenheim Foundation, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Konrad Adenhaer Inst., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Morris, James O., 1959-1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Myers, Clarks A., 1960-1971 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Netherlands Corresp., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Netherlands Corresp., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Netherlands Corresp., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Netherlands Corresp. 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Netherlands Corresp. 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Netherlands Corresp. 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Netherlands Corresp. 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Netherlands Corresp. 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Netherlands Corresp., 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Pan American Union, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Russian Corresp., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Sayin, Afife, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Vande Vall, Mark, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Univ. of Geneva, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- U.S. Dept. of Labor - 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- U.S. Dept. of Labor - 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- U.S. Dept. of Labor - 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- U.S. Dept. of State 1954-1963 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- C (Box 3, Folder 40)